[{"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b852", "question": "What two baseball players make up the battery?", "answer": "The pitcher and the catcher", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937eaa908d98002fdd633a5", "question": "Which country owns Easter Island?", "answer": "Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adbb", "question": "What was the first US city to have a public school system?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a726", "question": "Alaska shares a common border with what other country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caa8", "question": "Which element has the atomic number 81?", "answer": "Thallium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a133", "question": "What is the name of Olive Oyl's brother?", "answer": "Castor Oyl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be5b", "question": "What rock band brought suit in 1994 claiming that Ticketmaster was an illegal monopoly?", "answer": "Pearl Jam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b89e", "question": "In what sport do the contestants throw salt before the contest?", "answer": "Sumo wrestling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396d1", "question": "The TV show \"King of the Hill\" was based in what US state?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b921", "question": "In fitness, what does the acronym \"BMI\" stand for?", "answer": "Body Mass Index", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef66126ce05a3942286e75", "question": "What state inspired Joni Mitchell's \"Big Yellow Taxi\"?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe766c3eec85e375820b289", "question": "What capital city is the only one located on the equator?", "answer": "Quito, Ecuador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb5", "question": "What country\u2019s air force was destroyed on the ground on June 5, 1967?", "answer": "Egypt\u2019s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4be", "question": "What is the technical term for what we commonly refer to as \"laser eye surgery\"?", "answer": "LASIK", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60062d69c9d816e292245c32", "question": "Who was the court sculptor of Alexander the Great?", "answer": "Lysippus of Sicyon, in the Peloponnese, was a contemporary of Alexander the Great, who made him his court sculptor.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5921fe82a4edfd43a087adcf", "question": "What does a ventriloquist typically hold on their lap?", "answer": "A puppet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefa9126ce05a3942286edb", "question": "What classic novel did TV's \"Big Brother\" get its name from?", "answer": "1984", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51aafff04d658268c9308", "question": "Who was Telemachus?", "answer": "Telemachus was the only son of Odysseus and Penelope.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ab1b2124fda37788a9a1db7", "question": "Armagnac is a brandy originating from which area of France?", "answer": "Gascony", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339671", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who hit Bart with his car?", "answer": "Mr. Burns", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea38baff048f679a45ab26", "question": "What is the average life cycle of a red blood cell?", "answer": "120 days", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecc1d7ec223966ae8f886e", "question": "The \"Tina\" in Tina Fey is short for what name?", "answer": "Stamatina", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2d1", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"Cump\"?", "answer": "William Tecumseh Sherman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "592eb17cf83302ff91e464a8", "question": "What cartoon by Mike Judge is the 1999 film \"Office Space\" based on?", "answer": "Milton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e9a6cebfabb9c85d8a97b", "question": "What type of food is \"Limburger\"?", "answer": "Cheese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c67c", "question": "Bruxism is a medical term for when a person does what?", "answer": "Grinds their teeth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ec22fc8dc25ca9e12ef62c", "question": "As whom was J\u00e1n Ludv\u00edk Hyman Binyamin Hoch better known?", "answer": "Robert Maxwell", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7d6", "question": "What do the face cards count for in the card game Gin Rummy?", "answer": "10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0a0", "question": "In what decade was the voting age in the US lowered to 18?", "answer": "1970's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133934b", "question": "Who was the first host of \"The Tonight Show\"?", "answer": "Steve Allen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbe696ce05a3942286eef", "question": "Who recorded the song, \"I Heard a Rumour\"?", "answer": "Bananarama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9dd", "question": "What organ of the body is particularly affected by hepatitis?", "answer": "Liver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffb68455dad637d903c8841", "question": "Which country, other than Switzerland, uses the Swiss franc?", "answer": "Liechtenstein", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a027", "question": "Which \"Family Guy\" character is employed as a pilot?", "answer": "Glenn Quagmire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393cc", "question": "In which James Bond movie does the character Pussy Galore appear in?", "answer": "Goldfinger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6000f0109a72b906b34e3cfa", "question": "Which unit of measurement is used by astronomers to measure the vast distances to objects outside our Solar System?", "answer": "Parsec, which is equal to 3.26 light years", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339165", "question": "What is the model name and number of the spacecraft's computer in \"2001: A Space Odyssey\"?", "answer": "HAL 9000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396b1", "question": "What good little witch is Casper's friend?", "answer": "Wendy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5bb", "question": "Which four US states share a border with Texas?", "answer": "Arkansas, Louisiana, New Mexico, Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339279", "question": "In season 14 of the TV show \"Big Brother\" what 5 players make up the quack pack?", "answer": "Dan, Danielle, Britney, Shane and Ian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d08181a1c922dd1ac64bf", "question": "Ulaanbaatar is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Mongolia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d55", "question": "Emilio Estevez was originally cast in what other actor's role in \"The Breakfast Club\"?", "answer": "Judd Nelson's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397cf", "question": "Who recorded the 1955 song \"Ain't That a Shame\"?", "answer": "Fats Domino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b84", "question": "Who was the first singer to have five #1 singles off of one album?", "answer": "Michael Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bdb", "question": "Which author won the Booker Prize 1986 for the novel \"The Old Devils\"?", "answer": "Kingsley Amis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339073", "question": "What is the author of \"The Bonesetter's Daughter\", \"The Joy Luck Club\", and \"Sagwa, the Chinese Siamese Cat\"?", "answer": "Amy Tan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff3d0364f032c0db195b498", "question": "Who were the five claimants to the Emperor of Rome in \"The Year of the Five Emperors\"?", "answer": "Pertinax, Didius Julianus, Pescennius Niger, Clodius Albinus and Septimius Severus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a04f", "question": "What was the only James Bond film to crack the top-ten list for highest grossing movies of the 1960s?", "answer": "Thunderball", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcfb", "question": "In 1934, five years before his retirement, who became the first athlete to appear on a Wheaties box?", "answer": "Lou Gehrig", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a3c837f039f3d7859290ff9", "question": "In the TV Show \"Gunsmoke\", what was Festus\u2019 occupation prior to becoming Marshall Dillon\u2019s deputy?", "answer": "Wolfer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c37bc815febcc896f9273", "question": "What is the tenth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Capricorn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5989a9bbcb8751d53e7d7601", "question": "What is the deadliest jellyfish in the world?", "answer": "Box Jellyfish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd72", "question": "What is sinology the study of?", "answer": "China", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f71c1a9e54d890926f6e5", "question": "Texas is home to the longest-running what?", "answer": "State fair -- Lasting 24 days, the Texas State Fair is one of Dallas's most popular events.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2e4", "question": "When was actor W. C. Fields born?", "answer": "1880", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cf16bb53d1af658864f2", "question": "Who does an angel placed on top of the Christmas tree represent?", "answer": "Archangel Gabriel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596dfcfa9616e6c6d4eba4f3", "question": "What year did the video game Grand Theft Auto V come out?", "answer": "2013", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d54", "question": "What year saw the release of the first Harry Potter book?", "answer": "1997", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8b88001dd7bf43be5e7eb", "question": "What is a group of snails referred to as?", "answer": "A walk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5feddbc66ce05a3942286d94", "question": "For what film did Meryl Streep win her first Oscar?", "answer": "\"Kramer Vs. Kramer\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5990afb8b72eedf883a8c70a", "question": "Where were the Pillars of Hercules located?", "answer": "Strait of Gibraltar", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c771", "question": "The Plato Scale is used specifically in the making of what beverage?", "answer": "Beer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff515afff04d658268c92eb", "question": "What two countries were involved in the Kargil War?", "answer": "India and Pakistan (the war took place between May and July 1999)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6b4", "question": "What is the official state tree of California?", "answer": "California Redwood", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c4c", "question": "Robert Downey Jr. received his first role in which movie?", "answer": "Pound", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69c8120565ad31a57c76d", "question": "What was the Old English name for the season after winter?", "answer": "Lent", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2d1", "question": "Which 1956 film did Bing Crosby, Grace Kelly and Frank Sinatra star in?", "answer": "High Society", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8aa2501dd7bf43be5e758", "question": "\"Cohen\" is Hebrew for what?", "answer": "Priest", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bde", "question": "Which fictional criminal has a sidekick called Bunny?", "answer": "Raffles", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b507", "question": "What is tripe on a menu?", "answer": "Stomach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b281", "question": "Who was the US president when the Dow Jones Industrial Average financially regained its pre-1929 peak?", "answer": "Eisenhower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a767", "question": "In which US state is Gettysburg National Military Park?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be28", "question": "What world's currency is the Linden dollar?", "answer": "Second Life", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a613", "question": "Name the largest landlocked country in Europe?", "answer": "Belarus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59524044736d4be723796b60", "question": "What island is the most populous in Canada?", "answer": "Island of Montreal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a633", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Peace Garden State\"?", "answer": "North Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff3cffa4f032c0db195b495", "question": "What was the name of the military nobility of medieval and early-modern Japan?", "answer": "Samurai", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b60c", "question": "\"Shrimp on the barbie\" is a seafood dish with origins in what country?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339046", "question": "What year did Wagner compose \"Tannhauser\"?", "answer": "1845", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a35e", "question": "Where is the International Court of Justice?", "answer": "The Hague", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6010c7200775fa611bce67d6", "question": "What was Kellogg's Frosted Flakes original name?", "answer": "When the breakfast cereal was introduced in 1952, it was called \"Kellogg's Sugar Frosted Flakes of Corn\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9a0", "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano \"Taal\"?", "answer": "The Philippines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600787ce0eee65b76b9f265d", "question": "According to Greek mythology who was the first woman on earth?", "answer": "Pandora", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ade3", "question": "What was Liu Bang, founder of the Han Dynasty, posthumously known as?", "answer": "Emperor Gaozu of Han", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fdd", "question": "What musician had a first name from Roman myth and the even more unusual middle name \"Sphere\"?", "answer": "Thelonious Monk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feccc10ec223966ae8f88a0", "question": "What book did Jesse Eisenberg purchase during rehearsals for \"The Social Network\"?", "answer": "\"C ++ For Dummies\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e66", "question": "When subjects of \"Who's Who\" pass away, what companion volume do they move to?", "answer": "Who Was Who", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c34b", "question": "Which letter in the Greek alphabet is a circle with a horizontal dash through the center?", "answer": "Theta", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e49", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"The Dirty Dozen\"?", "answer": "Jim Brown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bbc954160f0007efaba0e61", "question": "What is entamaphobia?", "answer": "Fear of doors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bfdfecdb668d7dfe168b5b1", "question": "On whose 1989 \"Trash\" release were Steven Tyler and Jon Bon Jovi guest performers?", "answer": "Alice Cooper's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c92d877e98cb977789f0", "question": "What European city hosts an annual wine-throwing festival?", "answer": "Haro, Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0ef", "question": "Fear of the color white is known as what?", "answer": "Leukophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a84f", "question": "The Niagara Falls name is derived from an Iroquois word meaning what?", "answer": "Thunder", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8f43601dd7bf43be5e81f", "question": "In the business world, NASDAQ stands for what?", "answer": "National Association of Securities Dealers Automated Quotation", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c831", "question": "The \"Wandering\" species of what bird has the longest wingspan in nature?", "answer": "Albatross", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfb4", "question": "In telephony, what do the initials ISDN stand for?", "answer": "Integrated Services for Digital Network", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388a0", "question": "What is the name of Dr. Seuss's egg-hatching elephant?", "answer": "Horton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a899dd160d398dc9cf7a6af", "question": "Who was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1973?", "answer": "Henry Kissinger", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9bc", "question": "What does \"Honolulu\" translate to in English?", "answer": "Sheltered harbor", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339575", "question": "What was nominated for an outstanding animated program Emmy in 1990?", "answer": "The Simpson's Christmas Special", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523cda736d4be723796b3b", "question": "Which city is home to the Blue Jays baseball team?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf96", "question": "What is the fear of tapeworms known as?", "answer": "Taeniophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133936a", "question": "What was Indiana Jones' dad afraid of in the movie \"Indiana Jones and The Last Crusade\"?", "answer": "Rats", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a93a", "question": "What hometown of Scott Joplin and Ross Perot is named for the three states whose border it sits near?", "answer": "Texarkana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc10cec223966ae8f8864", "question": "In the 2007 Superbowl, a player used what piece of equipment to make a catch?", "answer": "Helmet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b1c", "question": "In what 1992 movie does Jennifer Jason Leigh play a dangerous \"roommate from Hell\"?", "answer": "Single White Female", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b88d", "question": "In which city would you find Wembley stadium?", "answer": "London", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e00", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek goddess Hestia?", "answer": "Vesta", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c502fbde8045e48466a5", "question": "What is chionophobia?", "answer": "Fear of snow.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca1d", "question": "Almonds are members of what family?", "answer": "Rose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4e5", "question": "What is steak tartare?", "answer": "A dish made of finely chopped raw beef", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b322", "question": "What Asian leader was known as the \"little brown saint\"?", "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff519ebff04d658268c9303", "question": "Which nihilist philosopher famously spoke of \"the death of God?\"", "answer": "Friedrich Nietzsche's philosophy predicted the erosion of organized religions and ethical frameworks.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b082", "question": "What famous woman became known as \"The Lady with the Lamp\" during the Crimean War?", "answer": "Florence Nightingale", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397a1", "question": "What award winning 1994 Tim Robbins movie was shot at the Ohio State Reformatory?", "answer": "The Shawshank Redemption", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcba", "question": "What model was married to musician Seal?", "answer": "Heidi Klum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cc3e96de0eb824d4052ef", "question": "In Alaska, it\u2019s legal to shoot bears, but illegal to do what to one?", "answer": "Wake one up", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba0", "question": "Saint Petersburg is located on which river?", "answer": "Neva River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3bf", "question": "What does a coleopterist study?", "answer": "Beetles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be68", "question": "What is Yankee Stadium's nickname?", "answer": "The House That Ruth Built", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcbc", "question": "What model was married to musician Mick Jagger?", "answer": "Jerry Hall", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69dce20565ad31a57c77d", "question": "Where did the concept of \"rolling out the red carpet\" originate?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c46b", "question": "What sign of the zodiac is represented by an archer?", "answer": "Sagittarius", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe69fc820565ad31a57c790", "question": "Where did the \u201cwiki\u201d in Wikipedia come from?", "answer": "Hawaiian for \"fast\" or \"quick\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9f1", "question": "What is the fear of social situations called?", "answer": "Sociophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d076a4870e6f05ba60085c", "question": "Shakespeare's \"The Taming of the Shrew\" depicts the courtship of which characters?", "answer": "Petruchio and Katherina", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be8", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"A Clockwork Orange\"?", "answer": "Anthony Burgess", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5bd", "question": "Who explored the Hudson River in 1609?", "answer": "Henry Hudson", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1cc", "question": "What film starred Michael Caine and Angie Dickinson?", "answer": "Dressed to Kill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b36c", "question": "Laika was the first ever dog to do what?", "answer": "Go into space", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b76a", "question": "How many colors were there in the first boxes of Crayola crayons sold in 1903?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339311", "question": "In the movie \"Dirty Dancing\", what did Baby carry?", "answer": "A watermelon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7ce32877e98cb97778a3e", "question": "The famous commercial port of Sidon is located in which Arab country?", "answer": "Lebanon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4ab", "question": "The asterism commonly called the \"Big Dipper\" can be seen in which constellation?", "answer": "Ursa Major", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a502", "question": "What are the first four digits of Beverly Hill' zip code?", "answer": "9021", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c35", "question": "What group of artists was known for its paintings of the Catskill Mountains?", "answer": "Hudson River School", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58b36e121c3f17ccc40c8e08", "question": "What common household object appears in the opening scene of the film \"The Sixth Sense\"?", "answer": "A light bulb", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab960586faa38a764be51a", "question": "What former republic did the Trabant originate from?", "answer": "East Germany, or German Democratic Republic", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb24", "question": "What soft drink called itself \"The Un-Cola\"?", "answer": "7-Up", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa6206ce05a3942286ecb", "question": "In which city does the film \"Home Alone 2\" take place?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b651", "question": "The name of what ancient game is derived from the Hindu word for twenty-five?", "answer": "Pachisi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b0e9cc964118b2bb3809cd", "question": "Who is the Greek counterpart to Cupid?", "answer": "Eros", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b88b", "question": "What is the point value of the letter Z in a standard Scrabble game?", "answer": "10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4e8e306d333868d34d74e", "question": "Where was the U.S.-backed Panama Canal originally supposed to be built?", "answer": "Nicaragua", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f16a27f7c52aae91cc07d8", "question": "Who is the son of Sycorax in Shakespeare's \"The Tempest\"?", "answer": "Caliban", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ae", "question": "The Great Pee Dee River flows into what body of water?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c52a", "question": "What is both a type of bed and a layer of the rainforest?", "answer": "Canopy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab83", "question": "What year did Sierra Leone gain its independence from the UK?", "answer": "1961", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febd82a7e83c707845b2175", "question": "What type of bird does Andy encounter in Brooks' office in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Crow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c292", "question": "What color is diamond dust?", "answer": "Black", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59675d002b59efe0e9417e96", "question": "The color of your tongue is pink only if it's what?", "answer": "Germ-free", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59049aaecf93664eb1048699", "question": "Who was Joe\u2019s co-creator for the character of Superman?", "answer": "Jerry Siegel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe1ecbc145fb29466707388", "question": "Where did fondue originate?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4c7c49076251badbead5", "question": "Which newspaper incorrectly reported Thomas E. Dewey defeated Harry S. Truman in the 1948 U.S. Presidential Election?", "answer": "Chicago Daily Tribune -- Now known as Chicago Tribune, it had once referred to Truman as a \"nincompoop\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefa49c6ce05a3942286eb5", "question": "The Stay Puff Marshmallow Man originally appeared in which film?", "answer": "Ghostbusters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab183cbaab681b09292188", "question": "Which racing team introduced a six-wheeled race car in 1974 and began racing it in 1976?", "answer": "Tyrrell Racing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a689", "question": "Which US state is home to the manmade Fort Peck Lake?", "answer": "Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58dba59f874c93a3298b2152", "question": "What talk show has Chris Hardwick hosted on AMC immediatley following the TV show \"The Walking Dead\"?", "answer": "The Talking Dead", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5cc", "question": "Concord is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "New Hampshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea3c8aff048f679a45ab40", "question": "Chromophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Colors", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65620ae7e414034b5aec1", "question": "Dionysus was the Greek god of what?", "answer": "Wine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c36", "question": "The Newbery Medal is awarded annually for what genre of writing?", "answer": "Children's literature", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af77", "question": "What collapsed in 1928 near the city of Santa Paula, killing over 450 people?", "answer": "St. Francis Dam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389b2", "question": "Which city staged the premier of \"Gone with the Wind\" that actress Hattie McDaniel couldn't attend due to her skin color?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b206", "question": "On what saint's day in 1572 did Catherine de Medicis have 3,000 Protestants killed in Paris?", "answer": "St. Bartholomew's Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a00d", "question": "What was the real first name of David Soul's \"Hutch\" on \"Starsky and Hutch\"?", "answer": "Ken", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf59", "question": "Who wrote the mIRC chat software?", "answer": "Khaled Mardam-Bey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8dccec223966ae8f8858", "question": "What film character says: \"My mama always said life was like a box of chocolates, you never know what you're gonna get\"?", "answer": "Forrest Gump", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390cb", "question": "What year did Jean Anouilh write the play \"L'Alouette\"?", "answer": "1952", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe36ce40ada16518afdc03e", "question": "What car company makes the Econoline van", "answer": "Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e59ffe83fe1f2a824bc2", "question": "Who assassinated the President of the Democratic Republic of the Congo, Laurent Kabila, in 2001?", "answer": "His bodyguard", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399a1", "question": "What 1997 film featured Clint Eastwood, Gene Hackman, Ed Harris, and E.G. Marshall?", "answer": "Absolute Power", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd82088d0de9af39e9d469e", "question": "How many countries were a part of the Soviet Union?", "answer": "15", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b4be01dd7bf43be5e7c6", "question": "Why were bowler hats invented?", "answer": "To protect gamekeepers from low branches", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abd2", "question": "What is the capital of Bermuda?", "answer": "Hamilton", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a851", "question": "What site is the home to the famous Intihuatana stone?", "answer": "Machu Picchu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa17", "question": "What country borders Egypt to the south?", "answer": "Sudan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa55bbc73aa70ea0b70b26", "question": "In which Asian city is the historic waterfront called The Bund?", "answer": "Shanghai", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c98a", "question": "What is Virga?", "answer": "Precipitation that doesn\u2019t reach the ground", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c810", "question": "A deficiency of which vitamin can lead to night blindness?", "answer": "A", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2cff32596a59cbdfbd375", "question": "Who said, \"Nearly all men can stand adversity, but if you want to test a man's character, give him power\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea4593ff048f679a45ab95", "question": "Who described the rings of Saturn as \"ears of a teacup\"?", "answer": "Galileo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133affe", "question": "After defeating Martin Van Buren, who died of pneumonia shortly after taking office?", "answer": "William Henry Harrison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf1f", "question": "Alphabetically, which is the last of Santa's reindeers?", "answer": "Vixen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6007804ebd51d85e222ab643", "question": "What offshoot of Cubism was influenced by the work of dye chemist Eug\u00e8ne Chevreul?", "answer": "Orphism\u00a0or\u00a0Orphic Cubism focused on pure abstraction and bright colors. The movement was influenced by Fauvism.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe767f1eec85e375820b29b", "question": "Which US state is named after a British island?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5977442d284458f1d785442d", "question": "The original name of New York City was what?", "answer": "New Amsterdam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ae95d6574a5ce6b56b825a", "question": "By what name is Beethoven's sixth symphony known?", "answer": "The Pastoral Symphony", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afda", "question": "Who was America's adversary at the Battle of Midway?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f7", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Treehouse of Horror V,\" what does Homer turn into a time machine?", "answer": "A toaster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c0c", "question": "What year was Barbra Streisand born in?", "answer": "1942", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e94cf395ea27d7a1303aece", "question": "Which rapper went platinum with his 2014 Album \"2014 Forest Hills Drive\"?", "answer": "J. Cole", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef60d76ce05a3942286e4c", "question": "Which comic book company was founded as Timely Publications?", "answer": "Marvel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b32a", "question": "Florence Nightingale tended the soldiers in which war?", "answer": "Crimean", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c594", "question": "What is the alligator pear better known as?", "answer": "An avocado", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd81c6dd0de9af39e9d4684", "question": "What common breakfast food was used to make bombs during World War II?", "answer": "Bacon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ea", "question": "In which US state is Stone Mountain?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2d9", "question": "How many sides does a nonagon have?", "answer": "Nine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990f510fa5fdd6dd25324eb", "question": "Central African Republic gaines its independence from which European country in 1960?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d60", "question": "Who is often considered the first to become a billionaire writing books?", "answer": "J.K. Rowling", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbdc", "question": "What is the name of the Cheeto's Cheetah?", "answer": "Chester", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f0b", "question": "What author created the character of James Qwilleran?", "answer": "Lilian Jackson Braun", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae53", "question": "What was the name given to the first German democracy established in 1919?", "answer": "Weimar Republic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a782", "question": "What line of Latitude lies at 23 degrees and 27 minutes north of the equator?", "answer": "Tropic of Cancer", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe0003b1cf6db9ac4808d0f", "question": "What is the tallest building in South America?", "answer": "Gran Torre Santiago, Santiago, Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59029e1bcad1ec93f27df753", "question": "Who wrote the essay \"A Nice Cup of Tea\"?", "answer": "George Orwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ca3eaf44f0f6af5b06664d", "question": "What is the capital of New Hampshire?", "answer": "Concord", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe1ecd7145fb29466707389", "question": "Where did the first Dunkin' Donuts open?", "answer": "Quincy, Massachusetts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9fb", "question": "Which natural phenomenon can be measured on the Mercalli scale?", "answer": "Earthquakes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ded065ea2747c8aff16d27", "question": "In which city would you find the Sistine Chapel?", "answer": "Vatican City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e9", "question": "What was writer and war hero T.E. Lawrence popularly known as?", "answer": "Lawrence of Arabia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a066", "question": "What was the name of John Lennon and Cynthia Lennon's son?", "answer": "Julian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a298", "question": "In musical terms, what does \"Da capo\" mean?", "answer": "From the beginning", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a66b", "question": "Which US state is home to White Sands National Monument?", "answer": "New Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a921", "question": "What nation is home to the Komodo dragon?", "answer": "Indonesia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b76e", "question": "\"Old Scratch\" is a nickname for whom?", "answer": "Satan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4afd49076251badbeabf", "question": "What was the first food to be intentionally microwaved?", "answer": "Popcorn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad86", "question": "Who was the first person to make a public encyclopedia?", "answer": "Denis Diderot", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ae9566574a5ce6b56b8254", "question": "What animals does a hippophobe fear?", "answer": "Horses", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398f4", "question": "What was Maxwell Smart\u2019s agent number on \u201cGet Smart\u201d?", "answer": "86", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c5dafbde8045e48466b1", "question": "An \"unkindness\" refers to a group of what animal?", "answer": "Ravens -- They have a bad reputation, and have been considered bad omens for centuries.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b3236bdbf195a31e15d73be", "question": "\"Oliver's Story\" was the sequel to which best-seller by Erich Segal?", "answer": "Love Story", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefc0776ce05a3942286f09", "question": "Who played the judge in the 1997 film \"Rainmaker\"?", "answer": "Danny Glover", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe52c131bf59ab7d2e38106", "question": "Bubble wrap was originally designed to be what?", "answer": "Wallpaper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f7147a9e54d890926f6dd", "question": "The second highest mountain on land is K2.  What does the letter \"K\" stand for?", "answer": "Karakoram -- K2 is located in the Karakoram Mountain Range.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f2", "question": "A Sone is a unit of what?", "answer": "Loudness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefbf506ce05a3942286efe", "question": "Who played the female lead in the film \"Man on Fire\"?", "answer": "Dakota Fanning", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac6a", "question": "What name was Haitian dictator Francois Duvalier better known by?", "answer": "Papa Doc", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a618", "question": "The underground lake, The Lost Sea, is located in which US state's Craighead Caverns?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b8cf2f94b094db915830ae", "question": "The Bical grape originates from which European country?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c2", "question": "When the Corvette was first introduced in 1953, it was only available in what color?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2e0", "question": "How many honeybees does it take to make one teaspoon of honey?", "answer": "12", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe3f11c8b5801b8f54a7fbd", "question": "Which famed European palace inspired Washington, D.C.'s design?", "answer": "Versailles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f702ff048f679a45aae2", "question": "What kind of scientist was Luther Burbank?", "answer": "Botanist", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b734", "question": "Spotted dick is a traditional British confection of boiled suet pudding with what?", "answer": "Raisins", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be59", "question": "What kind of animal is Chuck E. Cheese?", "answer": "A mouse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d47071f8e329de4f877891", "question": "What year was cricketer Phil Tufnell born?", "answer": "1966", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af71", "question": "During what decade was the first US transcontinental railway completed?", "answer": "1860s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b523", "question": "What is the main difference between a supercharger and a turbocharger?", "answer": "Superchargers are usually belt driven, while turbochargers gas driven.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff141d3b0ee8c595b6d39a7", "question": "What artist is famous for the \"Helga Pictures\"?", "answer": "Andrew Wyeth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe69dba20565ad31a57c77b", "question": "In what year did the U.S. Census begin?", "answer": "1790", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b02a", "question": "What ousted Eastern European leader was executed on Christmas Day in 1989?", "answer": "Nicolae Ceausescu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a8d", "question": "What sitcom drew an audience of 80.4 million viewers for its final episode, in 1993?", "answer": "Cheers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6691ea5bfecdd737e0877", "question": "What is the main alcohol in a Moscow Mule?", "answer": "Vodka", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be8", "question": "The TV show \"Seinfeld\" is a show about what?", "answer": "Nothing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dab", "question": "What hitmaker produced the 2003 PlayStation music mixer game \"Beaterator\"?", "answer": "Timbaland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600242c44be4723ccac2218c", "question": "Which James Joyce novel chronicles a day in the life of Leopold Bloom?", "answer": "\"Ulysses\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abe6", "question": "What country borders Guatemala to the north?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff51739ff04d658268c92fa", "question": "The bottom of King Tutankhamun's sandals depicted what?", "answer": "His enemies -- A painting of his enemies was found on the soles, which allowed him to trample on his enemies for all of eternity.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be51", "question": "What Major League Soccer team signed David Beckham to a $50 million contract in 2007?", "answer": "The Los Angeles Galaxy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7f9", "question": "What is the surgical knife called an \"izmel\" used for?", "answer": "Circumcision at a bris", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b89d", "question": "What do golfers call a putt that is short enough to be conceded?", "answer": "A gimme", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce6", "question": "What is Mr. Freeze's given name?", "answer": "Victor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b835", "question": "What color flag is waved to indicate \"caution\" in auto racing?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339781", "question": "What does the name of the Finnish band HIM stand for?", "answer": "His Infernal Majesty", "category": "entertainment"}]